designerapparel.com 2019-12-31

# ShopStyle: Privacy Policy

Updated: [Dec 16, 2019]

Effective Date: January 1, 2020 This Privacy Policy describes how ShopStyle Inc. ("we," "us," "our," "Company") collect, use, share, and protect information in connection with the Company websites, mobile websites, mobile applications, browser applications, and any related services that refer or link to this Privacy Policy ("Services"). ShopStyle is part of the [Rakuten Group](https://global.rakuten.com/corp/about/company/ "Rakuten Group"), which includes the affiliates and subsidiaries of our parent company Rakuten, Inc., based in Tokyo, Japan. 

**1\. Collection of Information.**

When you use our Services, we may collect or receive Personal Information about you to provide our services and operate our business. "Personal Information" means information that can be used to identify you (whether alone or in combination with other data). The types of Personal Information that we may collect about you are: 

**Information You Provide to Us Directly**

We collect, process, and use your information when you:

  * Register for our Services or sign into an existing account
  * Visit our website(s)
  * Access our Services through our application(s)
  * Connect to our Services using third-party accounts, such as your email, or social media 
  * Contact us for support
  * Participate in our shopping
  * Enter a sweepstakes, contest, promotion, survey, or poll

The Personal Information you may provide to us includes:

  * First and last name
  * Username and password
  * Email address
  * Mailing address and phone number for sweepstakes, contest, and promotion entries and tax information for sweepstakes, contest, and promotion winners 
  * Profile picture
  * Your location
  * Preferred gender category of clothing
  * Favorite stores and products
  * Sale alerts

**Information Collected Automatically**

We and our service providers automatically collect certain information about you through: 

  * Interaction with our Services
  * Cookies and other tracking technologies
  * Location-identifying technologies
  * Monitoring and analyzing trends, usage, and activities

The information that we may collect automatically based on your use of the Services: 

  * The nature of the product or service requested or purchased
  * How you connect to our Services, such as your IP address, unique device identifiers, device or session IDs, and information regarding the network and connected hardware (e.g., computer or mobile device and carrier), and system configuration information 
  * Browsing, shopping, and purchase history
  * Your geolocation, to the extent you have configured your device to permit us to collect such information, date and time stamps associated with transactions, and locale preferences 
  * Click-stream data (internet or other electronic information regarding you browsing history, search history, the web page visited before you came to our website, length of visit and number of page views, click-stream data meaning the page-by-page paths you take as you browse through our Services) 
  * Data we receive from third party websites, services, and products when you interact with Social Features of our Services described in Section 10 below 

**2\. How We Use the Information We Collect.**

We may use information about you in the following ways:

**Manage Your Account**

If you provide us with Personal Information, we may use it to: (i) process your registration with our Services, including verifying whether your email address is active and valid and enrolling you into our programs; (ii) monitor and manage your account; (iii) track your shopping, deliver you any rewards or payments, and identify opportunities for rewards and/or offers; (iv) send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and administrative messages; (v) provide you customer service regarding your account and reply to your questions, comments and requests; and (vi) comply with legal and regulatory provisions in force and with the competent judicial authorities in each geographical jurisdiction that the Company operates in. We may also use your information to assess risk and prevent fraud. 

**Improve Our Services**

We may process information through analyzing and monitoring usages and trends and performing statistical analyses to improve our Services and the websites, applications, marketing efforts, and the products and services of our affiliates to provide a better service to you in the future. We may also use this information to adapt Service content to be more likely be of interest to you. 

**Provide You Marketing Information**

To the extent permitted by applicable law or subject to your consent, we may use your Personal Information to provide you more personalized offers and/or special offers, discounts and similar information, and to send you newsletters, rewards, discounts, promotion codes, events, and general information about the Service. To match your profile and interest, we may create a profile of your preferences and provide personalized advertisements, content or features. You can manage these communications in accordance with Section 4 (Your Choices) below. 

**Administer Contests, Sweepstakes, and Promotions**

From time to time, we may invite you to enter sweepstakes, contests, promotions, surveys or polls. If you choose to participate in a contest or promotion, your Personal Information may be used to administer the contest, such as to determine your eligibility for the contest or to award a prize. 

**3\. Why We Share Information.**

We may share the information we collect, including your Personal Information, with third parties under the following circumstances. 

**Service Providers and Business Partner**

We only share your Personal Information with third parties to operate our Services. We may share your Personal Information with our service providers that perform marketing services and other business operations on our behalf, under our instructions and in compliance with appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect your Personal Information. For example, we may partner with other companies to provide you support services, authentication services, prevent fraud on our Services, administer our promotions, referral programs, sweepstakes, and surveys, perform analytics, maintain the accuracy of our databases, and fulfill your product purchases. We may rent, sell, and share information, that cannot be used to directly identify you, and does not include any payment information, with merchant partners, third parties, or affiliates. Please note that the below companies may collect information about you when you interact with our Services, including digital identifiers and information about how you interact with the offers and ads presented in our Services. The information collected may be used for a variety of purposes such as personalization of offers or ads, analytics on how users engage with websites or ads, and improvement of the advertising services of these companies. For more information about the collection, use and sale of your Personal Information, and your rights, please use the below links. 

**Rakuten Group Companies**

We work closely with our affiliated businesses and companies within the Rakuten Group and share your Personal Information for our internal business administration. We may also share your account credentials (username, email address, encrypted password) and related personal identification (first and last name and address) and other personal information with the Rakuten Group for internal business administration and to improve their websites, applications, marketing efforts, and products and services. The Rakuten Group may rent, sell, and share information, that cannot be used to directly identify you and does not include any payment information, with merchant partners, third parties, or affiliates. 

**Protection of Rights and Other Legal Purposes**

We may share the information we collect, including Personal Information, to the extent permitted by applicable law, (i) in response to subpoenas or other legal process or if in our good faith opinion such disclosure is required or permitted by law; (ii) at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation, including, but not limited to, meeting law enforcement requirements; (iii) to defend our terms and conditions or other policies applicable to our Services; and (iv) to protect the rights, property, life, health, security and safety of us or any third party. 

**Business Transfers**

We may share the information we collect, including Personal Information, with any third party in connection with, or during negotiations of, any proposed or actual merger, purchase, sale (including a liquidation, realization, foreclosure, or repossession), or any other type of acquisition of all or any portion of Company assets, conveyance or transfer of all or a portion of our business to another company. 

**4\. Your Choices**

In some cases, you may have the option to decline providing us information. However, your choice to not provide information may impact your use of certain features or services. You may unsubscribe or opt out of receiving marketing emails from us by using the unsubscribe link on the footer of our marketing emails, by logging into your account settings, or by using the Contact Us option through the Services. Upon written request, we will provide you with information on whether we hold any Personal Information. We encourage you to maintain the accuracy of the information you submit to us, such as the information you provide us to register for your account. The Services may allow you to access, review, correct, update, and remove or make inaccessible Personal Information you have provided through your account settings. You may provide account updates and changes by logging into your account and changing settings or by using the Contact Us option through the Services. With respect to our mobile and other applications, you can prospectively stop all collection of information by the application by uninstalling the application. You may at any time opt out from further allowing us to have access to your mobile location data by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device. We will make good-faith efforts to make requested changes in our then-active databases as soon as reasonably practicable. We will respond to your requests within a reasonable timeframe. 

**5\. Data Security and Retention.**

We take reasonable measures to protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. We use a secure, encrypted connection (using a TLS protocol) on all pages where you access or transmit Personal Information. Although we use reasonable efforts to help protect your information, transmission via the Internet is not completely secure and Company cannot guarantee the security of your information collected through our Services. Except as otherwise set forth under applicable law, we assume no liability or responsibility for disclosure of your information due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third-party access, or other causes beyond our control. 

We retain the information collected via our Services until such time as you choose to close your account. After that time, we may aggregate the data and retain it for analytical purposes. We may also retain your information on backup media to comply with applicable law, to support financial audits, to resolve disputes, to maintain compliance efforts, and for other legitimate business reasons. 

**6\. Promotional Communications.**

By signing up for an account, you may receive periodic emails from us. You can opt out of receiving such communications from us at any time by (i) following the instructions provided in those communications; (ii) modifying your Email Preferences in the Account Settings of your account; or (iii) contacting us through the Services. 

Please note that even if you opt out of receiving promotional communications, we may continue to send you non-promotional emails and other types of communications, as permitted by law, such as service emails relating to our ongoing business relationship. Service emails contain service-related announcements that affect your account, such as product order confirmations, reward or payment updates, and responses to your comments and feedback submitted to us. Company mobile applications, browser extensions, and websites may send you notifications, such as alerts, sounds, and icon badges. Push notifications or in-app messages may include both operational messages and promotional messages regarding products, services, and offers that may be of interest to you. When using mobile applications, push notifications and other mobile alerts can be configured in the settings of your mobile device. As with emails, even if you opt out of receiving promotional communications, we may continue to send you non-promotional push notifications, such as those about your use of the applications or our ongoing business relations. 

**7\. Cookies.**

We and our partners use cookies and similar technologies to automatically collect information about your use of the Services, including to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We use cookies for many purposes, including, without limitation, authentication, tracking user preferences or web pages visited while using our Services. You may control the use of cookies at the browser level. If you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on the Service. 

**8\. Analytics, Targeting, Tracking.**

We, and third parties with which we partner, may also use cookies, pixels, and other technologies to automatically collect information about your use of the Services, such as your click-stream data, browsing history, IP address, web browser, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked, and conversion information. Data collected from a particular browser or device may be used with another computer or device that is linked to the browser or device on which such data was collected (also known as cross-linking). We may also work with third parties to serve ads to you as part of a customized campaign on other websites or platforms. These third parties may also collect Personal Information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use our Services to help predict your preferences and to display (and to enable other third parties to display) ads to be more likely to be of interest to you. Some third-party service providers that we engage (including third-party advertisers) may also place their own cookies on your browser. Note that this Privacy Policy covers only our use of cookies and does not include use of cookies by such third parties. 

**9\. Third-Party Data.**

The Services contain hyperlinks to websites of merchants and retailers and other websites or locations that we do not control and are operated and controlled by third parties ("Third-Party Websites"). Our Privacy Policy does not apply to these Third-Party Websites and we make no representations regarding the policies or business practices of any such Third-Party Websites. 

**10\. Social Features.**

Certain functionalities on the Services are specifically designed to permit interactions that you initiate between the Services and third-party websites or services, including third-party social networks ("Social Features"). Examples of Social Features include features that enable you to transmit your account content from a third-party website or service to our Services; to "like" or "share" our Services’ content on other websites or services; to sign in to the Services using your username and password from a third-party site or service; and to connect our Services with a third-party website or service. If you choose to use Social Features, the information you post or provide access to may be used by us and/or publicly displayed on our Services or by the provider of the Social Feature that you use. Similarly, if you post information on a third-party platform that references our Services (e.g., by using a hashtag associated with Company in a tweet or status update), your post may be published on our Services in accordance with the terms of the third-party website or service. When you use our Services with a third-party site or service, both Company and the third party may have access to certain information about you and your use of our Services and the third-party site or service. In addition, we may receive information about you if other users of a third-party website give us access to their profiles and you are one of their "connections," or information about you is otherwise accessible through your connections’ web pages, profile pages, or similar pages on a social-networking or other third-party website or interactive service. The information we collect in connection with Social Features is subject to this Privacy Policy. The information collected and stored by the third parties remains subject to those third parties’ privacy policies, including whether the third parties continue to share information with us, the types of information shared, and your choices with regard to what is visible to others on those third-party websites or services. 

**11\. Referral Programs.**

We may offer features which allow you to inform an individual about our Services. If you choose to use our referral features, we will ask you for your referral’s email address to send them an electronic communication inviting them to join our Services. We will store this information for the sole purpose of sending this email and tracking the success of our referral program. If you choose to participate in our referral programs, you represent and warrant that you have a personal relationship with your referral and that you are authorized to share their information with us for the purpose of sending this communication to invite them to join the Services. If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your Personal Information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at [hi@shopstyle.com. ](mailto:hi@shopstyle.com "Email ShopStyle")

**12\. Rights Applicable to California Residents**

This section applies only to California residents.

**Personal Information Collected**

Pursuant to the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”), below is a summary of the Personal Information categories, as identified and defined by the CCPA (see California Civil Code section 1798.140 (o)), that we collect, the reason we collect your Personal Information, where we obtain the personal information, and the third parties with whom we share Personal Information. 

We may collect: (a) identifiers such as a name, address, unique personal identifier, email, phone number, your device’s IP address, software, and identification numbers associated with your devices; (b) commercial information such as records of products or services purchased, obtained, or considered by you; (c) internet or other electronic information regarding you browsing history, search history, the web page visited before you came to our website, length of visit and number of page views, click-stream data, locale preferences, your mobile carrier, date and time stamps associated with transactions, and system configuration information; (d) your geolocation, to the extent you have configured your device to permit us to collect such information; (e) audio recordings of your voice to the extent you call us, as permitted under applicable law; and (f) inferences about your preferences, characteristics, behavior and attitudes. We generally do not collect the following categories of Personal Information: your customer records; protected classifications; biometric information; professional or employment-related information; or education information. For more information about the Personal Information we collect, please refer to Section 1 (Collection of Information), above. 

We collect the above-identified categories of Personal Information for the business and commercial purposes described in Section 2 (How We Use of Information We Collect) of this Privacy Policy. For information about the categories of third parties with whom we share the above-identified categories of Personal information please see Section 3 (Why We Share Information) of this Privacy Policy. 

**Privacy Rights**

If you are a California resident, you have rights in relation to your Personal Information; however, your rights are subject to certain exceptions. For instance, we cannot disclose specific pieces of Personal Information if the disclosure would create a substantial, articulable, and unreasonable risk to the security of the Personal Information, your account with us or the security of our systems of networks. 

You have the right to know the Personal Information we collect, use, disclose, and sell about you during the preceding 12 months. You have the right to request in writing a copy of the categories of Personal Information we have collected about you, the categories of sources from which we collected that information, why we collected that information about you, the categories of third parties with whom we shared your Personal Information, the categories of Personal Information that we disclosed about you for a business purpose, and the specific pieces of Personal Information we have collected about you. Please note that we are only required to respond twice per calendar year to your right to know. Please visit our [Privacy Preferences Center](https://www.shopstyle.com/privacy/preferences) to make such a request. 

You have the right to request that we delete any Personal Information we have collected from you or maintain about you, subject to certain exceptions. Please visit our [Privacy Preferences Center](https://www.shopstyle.com/privacy/preferences) to exercise your right to delete your Personal Information. 

· We will not discriminate against you if you exercise your right to know, delete or to opt-out of sales, which is described below. 

· To verify your identity, we will ask you to login to your account and obtain a verification code from the email address associated with your account. If we cannot verify your identity from the information we have on file, we may request additional information from you, which we will only use to verify your identity, and for security or fraud-prevention purposes. 

We share Personal Information about you with our merchant partners, third parties or affiliates for providing rewards and benefits to you and for marketing purposes. In relation to certain instances of sharing we any may receive a benefit, which California law considers a “sale” of Personal Information. To the extent you do not want us to share your Personal Information with another party in this way, you have the right to opt-out of such sharing. If you would prefer to no longer have your Personal Information shared in this way, Please visit our [Privacy Preferences Center](https://www.shopstyle.com/privacy/preferences). Please note that to the extent you opt-out we may be unable to offer you some of our services which require such sharing of your Personal Information. 

**13\. Changes to Privacy Policy.**

This Privacy Policy is current as of the date set forth above. We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time consistent with applicable privacy laws and principles. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy we will notify you by revising the date at the top of this Privacy Policy, and where such changes will impact you as a data subject, we will provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to the homepages of our Services or sending you an email notification). 

**14\. Contact Us.**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us by email at [legal@shopstyle.com](mailto:legal@shopstyle.com "Email ShopStyle") or by mail at 800 Concar Drive, Suite 175, San Mateo, CA 94402, ATTN: ShopStyle Legal.
